#### JOANA ABA BAFFOE

(+233) 249095968 / (+233) 504765730 joannyaba@gmail.com

#### **CAREER OBJECTIVES**

To work in a position that will bring out my best and enable me contribute to the development of the organization. To exercise my analytical and relational skills in a multi-disciplinary environment, thereby contributing to achievement of the institution's objectives and vision. Also, to learn and thereby gain more practical, analytical and technical skills on business operation to create a strategic plan in order to help the organization attain its goals.

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Over three years of effective and efficient experience in human relation in the health, education and financial sector. Output achieved was geared toward the attainment of institutional mandate and goals. Exposure to new ideas and efficient strategy in human relation due to field experience.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### Achievement

**Institution:** Department of Social Welfare, Sekondi Sub-Metro **Output:** Rescued four abandoned babies to the orphanage home

Advocated for over 20 paupers in order to enjoy free medical treatment during

admission at the Takoradi Hospital.

**Duration:** August, 2014 – July, 2015

Roles: Social Worker **Responsibilities:** 

Counseling of clients

Embarking on investigations on clients

Writing of reports

Responsible for all administrative duties at the Social Welfare Department at Takoradi

Hospital.

Takoradi Hospital. **Institution:** 

Excellent management of the Social Welfare Unit of the Hospital. **Output:** 

**Duration:** August, 2015 – July, 2016

Roles: Social Worker

**Responsibilities:** Counseling of Patients on admission to overcome addictions or stress

Investigating background of patients to ensure tracing of relatives

Writing of reports

Advocating for clients on admission in order to ensure access good health care.

**Institution:** Tender Sprout International School

Output: Excellently prepared the class of CWB F (year 2-3) to their next upper class

**Duration:** September 2016 – July 2017

**Roles:** Main Provider (Tutor)

**Responsibilities:** Providing all the needed care and tuition to ensure holistic development of the children.

**Institution:** Key Port Management Company Limited

Output: Excellent and efficient management of Hope Restoration Center, Adabraka Polyclinic

**Duration:** September 2017 to date

**Roles:** Social Worker

**Responsibilities:** Counseling of women who have experienced miscarriage and still birth.

In charge of medical social work duties at hospital.

### SKILLS, INTERESTS AND STRENGTHS

### **SKILLS**

❖ Entrepreneurship and Business Plan Development.

❖ Computer Software: Windows, SPSS, Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, PowerPoint, and proficient use of internet for research.

## **INTERESTS**

Enjoy aerobics, decorating, designing, watching movies, listening to music, going for tour, and dancing.

#### **STRENGTHS**

- ❖ Exposure to interpersonal communication skills; well-presented and able to establish good working relationship with a range of different people.
- Eager to learn new things, develop new skills and take up new challenges.
- ❖ Ability to cope with failure and try to learn from them.

#### **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

♦ December 2009 – August 2010: Royal Bow Company Limited, Takoradi Branch, Ghana.

Position: Account Clerk

❖ August 2016 to July, 2017: Tender Sprout International School, East Legon, Ghana.

Position: Teacher

❖ July, 2017 to September, 2017: Capital Bank, Ghana,

Position: Business Ambassador

September, 2017 to date: Key Port Management Co. Ltd, Tema, Ghana.

Position: Social Responsibility Initiative Officer.

### NATIONAL SERVICE

11th September, 2014 to July 2015: Department of Social Welfare, Sekondi Sub-Metro.

Responsibilities: Worked as a Social Worker at Takoradi Hospital.

### **VOLUNTORY SERVICE**

September 2015- July 2016: Worked as a Social Worker at Takoradi Hospital.

### **EDUCATION**

♦ August 2010- June 2014: Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, Ghana. (BA. Sociology and Social Work)

**Some courses studied:** Organizational Behavior, Gender and Development, Industrial Sociology, Human Resource Management, Accounting, Social Psychology, Approaches to Counselling in Social Work and Nature and Theoretical Framework of Social Work Practice, Elements and Principles of Economics, Mathematics and Statistics for Economists, and Research Methods.

**Final Year Project:** The effect of goal setting theory of motivation on job satisfaction. A cross-sectional survey on organizations in the formal and informal sectors in Kumasi, Ghana.

October 2006- May 2009: Archbishop Porter Girls' Secondary School, Takoradi, Ghana. (Offered Business Accounting). September 1997- May 2006: Bethel Methodist Primary and Junior Secondary School, Takoradi, Ghana.

# **INTERNSHIP**

❖ June 2012 – July 2012: Donewell Insurance Company Limited, Takoradi Branch, Ghana. Responsibilities: Filing and issuing of new insurance policies and renewing of expired policies.

♦ 11<sup>th</sup> June, 2013- 2<sup>nd</sup> August, 2013: Takoradi Sub-Metro Mutual Health Insurance Scheme. Responsibilities: Auditing of claim forms, making entries of claims due to be paid and other secretarial duties; filing and photo copying.

# REFERENCES

Dr. Kofi Osei Akuoko

Senior Lecturer,

Department of Sociology and Social Work,

Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology.

Telephone number: +233208222886

Frank K. D. Appiah,

Claims Manager,

National Health Insurance Scheme,

Takoradi.

Telephone number: +233244887015

Mrs. Deborah Daisy Kwabia,

Metro Director,

Department of Social Welfare,

Sekondi.

Telephone number: +233233232652 / +233243232652

Dr. Linda Vanotoo,

Regional Director,

Ghana Health Service,

Greater - Accra.

Telephone number: +233208188757 / +233243714095